# Leonardo Herve Miceli

Josefa Negron Diaz 11 41940 Tomares (Sevilla, Spain)

Ihmiceli@gmail.com

+34 679 043 869

Android Developer with over ten years of software and web development experience in a broad range of industries, including travel industry, yellow pages categorized search, post marketing, and mobile stores. Solid understanding of full mobile and software development life cycles, UIX, web analytics, changing web standards, and Agile methodologies. Dedicated to continuously developing, implementing, and adopting new technologies to maximize development efficiency and produce innovative applications.

#### Core Qualifications

- Native Android Development
- Quality Assurance
- · Mobile Development Life Cycle
- User Experience Design
- · Information Architecture
- · Agile Software Development Methodologies

### **Education:**

03/2002 – 05/2007 **BS, Systems Engineering** 

Main focus: Computer science

# **Technical experience:**

Platforms: Linux/Unix, Windows NT/2000/XP, Android

Languages: Java, Kotlin, EJB3, JSF, JSP, SQL, C/C++, Ruby, JavaScript, AJAX,

XHTML, XML, JSTL, XSL, XPath, XSD, XML-Schema, Bash Scripting.

**Databases:** MySQL, Oracle, Postgres, Hibernate, JPA

IDE: Android Studio, Intellij Idea, Eclipse, Netbeans

Frameworks, architectures Room, Livedata/ViewModel, MVP, MVVM, Spring, JAXB, Node.js, Dojo, YUI,

jQuery, AngularJS, RequireJS, Bootstrap, Less, Apache Servicemix, Apache Cocoon, Apache Lenya, Apache Solr, Apache Nutch, Apache Tomcat, Jetty,

JBoss.

other: GIT, CVS, SVN, Accurev, JIRA, Mantis, Redmine, Agile, OpenOffice

#### **Experience:**

1/2017 – current Android Developer

sdos http://sdos.es

**Activities:** Software Design, Development.

Function: Analyst. Developing inditex's android applications (bershka, massimo dutti,

stradivarius, pull&bear, zarahome, etc)

3/2016 – 11/2016 Freelance android developer

Verse http://verse.chat/

Activities: Software Design, Development.

Function: Analyst

11/2011 – 9/2015 codeBusters S.L. - http://www.codebusters.es/

Activities: Software Design, Development.

**Function: Analyst** 

07/2014 - 10/2014 Project "Regtangular" for codeBusters

**Activities:** Open source tool developed by codebusters to automatically generate new web applications. The flexibility and scalability of the technologies as AngularJS, RequireJS, Bootstrap and others allow us to generate very high quality, responsiveness and customization in a short time thus very significantly reduce production costs.

https://github.com/codebusters/generator-reqtangular

Applications: Yeoman, AngularJS, RequireJS, Bootstrap, Grunt, Bower, Less,

Node.js

02/2014 – 09/2014 Project "Space and People – mobile App" for "Technologyblueprint (tbl)" and "Space and People"

**Activities:** Design and implementation of a mobile real time application with JavaEE backend for mall venue free space planing. Fully optimized to allow taking advantage of the new generation of 10" tablets. It allows user to drag and drop promotion and retails sites on the halls and hallways of shopping malls, and provides financial calculation to generate the most profitable strategies. Also it provides the ability to handle different site strategies for each venue, by specifying different time frames for each strategy. Includes helpful 5 year revenue prediction and the ability to email reports generated.

**Applications:** Node.js, Apache Cordova, Grunt, Bower, Require.js, Angular.js, Jquery, Underscore.js, D3.js, Dc.js, Bootstrap, Kinetic.js, Jboss, RESTeasy, Spring, Hibernate

Function: Analyst, Senior software engineer and quality control

08/2013 - 01/2014 Project "scraper - Web Tool for Data Mining" for codeBusters

**Activities:** Design and implementation of a web based real time application designed to automate data extraction from web based resources. Data can be stored in collection and used for the automatic generation of thin html5, css and javascript client for mobile and web. Early alpa version <a href="http://scraper.codebusters.es/">http://scraper.codebusters.es/</a>

**Applications:** Node.js, socket.io, Apache Solr, Apache CouchDB, Mongo, Redis, Apache Cordova, Jquery, JSON

Function: Analyst, Senior software engineer and quality control

11/2012 – 03/2013 Project "SVG Editor" for becompany.ch and post.ch

**Activities:** Development and bug fixing of application for editing of SVG postcards

### **Experience:**

online.

Applications: RequireJS, JavaScript, Bootstrap

Function: Analyst, Senior software engineer and quality control

04/2013 - 08/2013

Project "Sobu user behavior analyst" for becompany.ch and post.ch

Activities: Data analysis tool for sites usage, amount of clicks generated by publications

of each user, sales generated, etc.

Applications: Scala, Bootstrap, dc.js, d3.js, RequireJS.

Function: Senior software engineer, bugfixing, support.

11/2011 - 10/2014

Project "sobu - buy, share, earn" for becompany.ch and post.ch

**Activities:** Analysis, design and implementation of social network hub to publish your purchase on facebook, twitter and linkedin. Authentication can be done via your facebook/twitter account. The principal development is based on Cocoon3 and uses Apache ActiveMQ, Apache Shiro, JPA via Hibernate, Liquibase.

Applications: Apache Maven, Apache Cocoon3, Apache httpd, Apache ActiveMQ,

Apache Shiro, JPA via Hibernate, Liquibase. Social APIS

Function: Analyst, Senior software engineer and support.

2/2011 - 08/2011

**Project "Orbitz Finance" for ORBITZ.com** 

**Activities:** Analysis, bugfixing and design for many finance tools for the travel and hotel platforms, Credit card payment tools, Fraud detection, Oracle Financials integration. <a href="http://www.orbitz.com">http://www.orbitz.com</a>. Functions performed at company's HQ in Chicago, IL.

Applications: J2EE, Hibernate, Oracle, Apache Servicemix.

Function: Senior software engineer.

12/2010 - 01/2011

Project "Orbitz Leonardo Plugin" for ORBITZ.com

**Activities:** Analysis, bugfixing and design for a tool to provide image editing and selection for hotel owners to the online Orbitz platform. <a href="http://www.orbitz.com">http://www.orbitz.com</a>.

Applications: J2EE, Hibernate, Oracle, Apache Servicemix.

Function: Senior software engineer.

9/2010 - 11/2010

Project "Orbitz Dataloader" for ORBITZ.com

**Activities:** Analysis, bugfixing and design for scheduled applications that gather hotel content from syndicated services to the company's databases. <a href="http://www.orbitz.com">http://www.orbitz.com</a>.

Applications: J2EE, Hibernate, Oracle, Apache Servicemix, Apache Alfresco.

Function: Senior software engineer.

7/2010 - 08/2010

Project "Orbitz Hotel Content Enhancer" for ORBITZ.com

**Activities:** Analysis, bugfixing and design for tool to merge/sync hotel content across data obtained from many syndicated services. <a href="http://www.orbitz.com">http://www.orbitz.com</a>.

Applications: Ruby on Rails.

Function: Senior software engineer.

## **Experience:**

1/2010 – 06/2010 Project "Orbitz Hotel Content Management" for ORBITZ.com

Activities: Analysis, bugfixing and design for a new application to serve as CMS for

Orbitz Hotel Content. <a href="http://www.orbitz.com">http://www.orbitz.com</a>.

Applications: J2EE, Spring, Spring MVC, YUI, Alfresco.

Function: Senior software engineer.

6/2006 - 11/2009 Project "ilocal" for intelligenX

**Activities:** Analysis, bugfixing and design for the back end of yellow pages sites using proprietary engine for categorized searches, in the role of developer and, eventually, team leader/project manager.

Applications: J2EE, JSP, JUnit, CVS, Apache, Apache Tomcat.

Function: Senior software engineer, Team leader.

La	na	นล	α	e	s:
_~	9	чч	м	•	•

Spanish: native

**English:** fluent in spoken and written